LIMITED TO 20 SERVINGS A DAY!
（每日限定20位）
Twenty!
20！
-Yes, I made it in time. -Ouch!
-及时赶上 -好痛
I'm sorry.
对不起
It's okay…
没关系
-Mr. Soma. -Hanasaki.
-相马先生 -花琦
-Why are you here? -What about you?
-你怎么会在这里？ -那你呢？
You said you want soba.
你说你想吃荞麦面
You said you'd be at the cafeteria.
你说你会去自助餐
-Oh. -You were going to leave me behind.
你想撇下我
-It's delicious. -Delicious!
-真好吃
It's the classic, traditional flavor. Awesome.
经典传统口味 棒极了
It's just as I expected.
和我期待的一样
I've been wanting to come here for a long time.
我想来这里好久了
The Ginza Front City is so amazing.
那个银座前城好棒啊
There will be lots of new stores opening up too.
也会开很多新商店
It'll be great if they make a multiplex.
要是复合商场就太棒了
I might stop by every day after work.
我每天下班后也许会顺道过去
The Itami Group's Ginza Redevelopment Project has everyone's hopes up.
伊丹集团的银座再开发计划 让大家充满期待
Yeah, it's a huge project that's expected to change
是啊 那是预计能改变银座商圈的
the city of Ginza.
庞大计划
But thinking of Itami
可是想到伊丹
brought back bad memories.
就勾起不好的回忆
The heir?
那个公子？
Yes.
对
Stop this nonsense!
废话少说！
Do you know who you're speaking to?
你知道你在跟谁说话吗？
I'm getting really angry again.
一想起来又火大了
Stop reminding me of that.
别再让我想起那件事
It's ruining our meal.
会坏了我的胃口
That's right. Let's forget it.
没错 我们把它忘了吧
I forgot.
我忘了
-That was delicious. -Yeah.
-真美味 -没错
I wanted to try the croquette.
我一直很想吃那个可乐饼
The hashed beef and Naporitan too.
还有牛肉烩饭和意大利面
It's worth going back there to try their entire menu.
值得回去尝完他们所有餐点
I agree.
没错
But there are lots of other places I want to try too.
不过我还有好多想去吃的地方
Marunouchi has so many options for lunch.
不愧是丸之内 有好多午餐选择
Hello.
你们好
SEIICHIRO ITAMI HEIR TO THE ITAMI GROUP
（人事部 伊丹清一郎 伊丹集团继承人）
Why are you at headquarters?
你怎么会在总部？
I was transferred to HR a week ago.
一个星期前 我被调到人事部
I couldn't stay at the Shinjuku Branch after what happened.
那件事情发生后 我无法再待在新宿分行
Since you treated me so badly.
因为你们对我那么恶劣
You are the damn idiot.
你才是可恶的笨蛋
In the future,
你未来
you may become a manager over many people.
可能会成为管理很多人的社长
But right now,
但是此刻
you're a nobody!
你只是无名小卒！
Well, soon enough I'm sure I'll be sent to
我相信过不了多久
a big branch somewhere within the city.
我就会调去东京某间大分行
I see.
这样啊
I'm off to eat lunch now,
我现在要去吃午餐
do you know any good places?
你们能推荐一下吗？
-Good places… -There aren't any.
-不错的地方… -没有
This place is so barren.
这个地方非常无趣
-Right, Mr. Soma? -You're right.
-对吧 相马先生？ -你说的对
There were so many
新宿分行附近
good restaurants around the Shinjuku Branch.
明明有很多不错的餐厅
Bye.
再见
He gets me so mad!
太生气了
It's ridiculous that he didn't get punished
真荒谬 他想毁了一家公司
for trying to destroy a company.
竟然没有受到惩处
They probably couldn't
他们大概不敢
dispose of the son of Itami Group.
处置伊丹集团的公子
The person who made HR take care of him
要人事部关照他的人
is General Manager Shindo.
是真藤本部长
-Really? -Yeah.
-真的吗？ -真的
It would be a big problem if the chairman gets mad
要是伊丹会长生气
and decides to put the redevelopment project
决定银座再开发计划不与我们合作
down the drain.
问题就大了
The chairman apparently dotes on his son.
伊丹会长显然很溺爱儿子
I guess a stupid son still seems cute to his father.
我猜笨儿子在父亲眼中还是很可爱
-How nauseating. -Mr. Soma.
-真叫人恶心 -相马先生
How about some oysters?
要不要来点牡蛎？
-They're rock oysters. -You can eat them raw.
-是岩牡蛎呢 -可以生吃
You can also grill them.
也可以烤来吃
-That sounds good. -I want some too.
-听起来不错 -我也想吃
They're a bit pricey, though.
不过有点贵
Give us a discount. We haven't gotten paid.
给我们一点折扣 我们还没收到薪水
-I can't negotiate that. -What?
-别跟我讨价还价 -什么？
Wait. You pay for your meals here?
等等 你在这里吃饭要付钱？
Yes. He charges me for everything I eat and drink here.
是啊 我在这里所有吃的喝的 他都跟我收钱
Oh wow, I thought you weren't paying since you're his daughter.
我以为因为你是他女儿 所以不用付钱
No, he won't even give me a discount.
才不是 他连折扣都不给我
I can't spoil her like that.
我不能宠坏她
I have to draw the line there or else it would be
必须划清界线
rude to my customers.
不然对我的顾客不公平
You're amazing.
你真了不起
I knew you'd understand me, Mr. Soma.
我就知道相马先生懂我
Yes.
是
I'm so impressed with your parenting philosophy.
你教养子女的哲学令我佩服
-You're so understanding. -Not at all.
-你真的很能理解 -没有啦
I'm nothing compared to you.
我完全比不上你
JUNE 25TH WEDNESDAY
（6月25日 星期三）
What?
怎么会？
INSUFFICIENT FUNDS PLEASE TRY AGAIN
（余额不足 请重新操作）
Why?
为什么？
150,000 YEN
（十五万日元）
INSUFFICIENT FUNDS PLEASE TRY AGAIN
（余额不足 请重新操作）
What? My paycheck isn't deposited?
什么？我的薪水还没存入？
That can't be. Are you sure you're doing it right?
不可能 你确定你操作正确吗？
What?
怎么回事？
INSUFFICIENT FUNDS PLEASE TRY AGAIN
（余额不足 请重新操作）
Yes, this is Sales Division Two. Please wait.
这里是营业二部 请稍等
Mr. Sakata, it's accounting from Itami Holdings.
坂田次长 是伊丹控股的会计
Okay.
好的
ASSISTANT GM OF SALES DIVISION TWO
（营业二部次长 坂田）
Hello.
喂 您好
ITAMI HOLDINGS
（伊丹控股）
Mr. Sakata, the employees haven't received their salaries.
坂田先生 员工还没有收到薪水
What? Didn't receive them?
什么？还没收到？
That can't be.
不可能啊
There's trouble!
出事了！
-Ita… -Ita?
-伊… -伊？
-What's "Ita"? -Mr. Shibasaki, please calm down.
-伊什么？ -芝崎次长 冷静下来
-Go to the main meeting room. -What?
-去主楼会议室 -什么？
You two were chosen as members of the investigation committee.
你们两个被选为调查委员会成员
Investigation? For what?
调查什么？
The salary data of over 10,000 Itami Group employees
伊丹集团超过一万名员工的薪资资料
have disappeared!
不见了！
Disappeared?
什么？不见了？
-What will we do in this committee? -Not sure.
-我们在委员会里要做什么？ -不清楚
This is my first time in the main building.
这是我第一次进主楼
It really feels like a traditional bank.
感觉真的好像传统银行
Employees like us usually don't have a chance to visit
我们这种员工通常没机会
these types of meeting rooms.
参观这种会议室
I'm getting nervous.
我紧张起来了
General Manager Shindo.
真藤本部长
Good mor-- ouch!
早… 好痛！
The investigation committee's meeting regarding the lost salary data
薪资资料遗失的调查委员会议
will now begin.
现在开始
Right now, there is a huge commotion
此刻在伊丹集团的员工
among the Itami Group's employees and their families.
与他们的家人间引起巨大骚动
Chairman Itami is furious,
伊丹会长也很震怒
so our president has
因此本行会长
instructed the investigation committee
指派真藤本部长
to be made under Mr. Shindo's command.
指挥调查委员会
In order to solve this issue as quickly as possible,
为了尽速解决这个问题
we asked capable members from each department to join this team.
我们请每个部门的优秀人才 加入调查委员会
That's all of you.
就是在座各位
They're expecting a lot from us.
他们对我们期望很高
The sales representative will give us details
营业部代表将告诉大家
on the current status and situation.
目前的详细状况
-Mr. Sakata. -You know him?
-坂田先生 -你认识他？
He helped me a lot when I was in the Akasaka Branch.
对 我在赤坂分行时他常帮我
I'm Nakagawa, the Director of Sales Division Two.
我是营业二部部长中河
I'm Sakata. I'm in charge of the Itami Group.
我是负责伊丹集团的坂田
I received a call this morning at 9:35 from accounting at the Itami Group,
今天早上9点35分 我接到伊丹集团会计部的电话
saying that their salary hasn't been deposited even though it's payday.
说今天是发薪日 薪水却没有入账
I thought it wasn't processed, so I went to Operations…
我以为还没处理 便去了作业中心
SALARY TRANSFER LIST
（薪资转账处理结果总览）
We haven't received that data.
我们还没有收到资料
That can't be…
不可能
ITAMI HOLDINGS
（伊丹控股）
We found out that the data
我们发现
was never sent to the operations center.
资料并没有送到作业中心
Mr. Sakata, how are
坂田先生 薪资资料的传送
the salary data processed for the transfers?
是如何处理的？
For the Itami Group,
对于伊丹集团
we physically hand over this magnetic tape.
我们是实际递交这种磁带
Five days ago, on June 20th,
五天前 6月20日
I went to the accounting department
我前往伊丹控股的
at Itami Holdings
会计部
and received the data…
取得磁带
I placed it inside the designated locker in the Sales Division.
并将它放入营业部内指定的置物柜
TO THE OPERATION CENTER
（送往作业中心）
Usually from there, either Iseki or Kameda
之后 通常井关或龟田其中一个人
takes it to the Operation Center.
会将它送去作业中心
I was very busy that day,
那天我非常忙
so I left the office right away,
立刻离开了办公室
and when I came back the slips were gone,
回来后 那张纸条不见了
so I thought someone
所以我认为有人处理了
took care of it, and I failed to verify that.
我也没有再确认
But when I asked today,
但是我今天问他们
they both said that they did not process it.
两个人都说没有处理
We knew that the salary data for the Itami Group
我们知道伊丹集团的薪资资料
had to be sent in by that day,
必须当天送过去
but we all thought that someone else
但是我们都以为
had processed it.
是别人送去处理了
It was a lack of confirmation.
这是少了确认流程
I guess they had gotten complacent over time.
我猜他们做久了就疏忽了
A small open seam,
一个小裂缝
mistake,
失误
and minor negligence leads to a huge problem.
和疏忽会导致大问题
That's the risk we take as someone who works in a business
那就是在银行这种产业工作
like the bank.
要承担的风险
You guys
你们大家
seem to have forgotten that!
似乎都忘了这点
I'm very sorry!
我非常抱歉
This problematic incident matters for two reasons.
这个事件会造成两个问题
Number one. If by any chance this salary data
第一 万一薪资资料
is leaked to an outside source,
不幸泄漏到银行外
it will be the biggest failure in the history of Tokyo Daiichi Bank.
将会是东京第一银行史上最大的疏失
Second.
第二
The Itami Group's
是关于伊丹集团的
Ginza Redevelopment Project.
银座再开发计划
This is the greatest chance for us to place this bank
这是我们超越其他银行
above the rest.
最好的机会
But because of this incident,
但是因为这个事件
not only may we not become the coordinator,
不仅可能无法成为主要银行
we may also not even be able to take part in the project.
甚至无法参与该计划
Finding the data,
找到资料
and controlling the situation,
控制住状况
should be prioritized above all else.
应该列为最优先任务
Please remember that.
请牢记
Yes, sir.
是
Director Karashima.
辛岛部长
You've been investigating, right?
你在调查了 是吧？
Yes.
是
There's a possibility that it dropped
有可能在送往作业中心途中
somewhere on its way to the Operation Center,
掉落在某个地方
so security and other employees are searching everywhere from
因此安保人员和员工正到处搜查
the Sales Division, Foreign Exchange Division, and the Operation Center.
包括营业部、外币兑换部和作业中心
But we have not found it yet.
但是目前还没有找到
Either way,
不管怎样
finding the lost data is our top priority.
找到遗失的资料是首要之务
Um…
请问…
What is it, Hanasaki?
什么事 花琦？
Isn't there a possibility
有没有可能
that it was stolen?
东西是被偷了？
Are you saying that someone in Sales Division Two
你是说有营业二部的人
stole the data?
偷了资料吗？
Ah… no, but…
不是
we can't rule out the possibility that it was stolen
不过不能排除有人蓄意
due to someone's malicious intent.
将东西偷走的可能性
-Search that route. -Yes, sir.
-也往那个方向搜查 -是
Work hard.
那么大家加油
Yes, sir.
是
Mr. Karashima, a word please.
辛岛部长 借一步说话
What's wrong with you?
你有什么毛病啊？
I told you to be quiet!
我叫你别乱讲话了！
-Sorry, I couldn't resist… -There you go again. You couldn't resist.
-对不起 我不小心… -又来了 你不小心
I'll fine you the next time you say that.
下次你再说 我要罚你钱
-500 yen each time. -How expensive!
-一次500 -太贵了！
Let's start by checking the entry record for the sales floor.
我们从营业部楼层进出记录查起
Let's also check the security camera.
还要查看监视器
Oh yeah, that's right.
对 没错
Hold on. We will do that.
等等 那个由我们做
We can't give such
我们不能把这么重要的任务
important tasks to Branch Inspection.
交给稽核班
Mr. Kodama, we can appoint tasks on our own, right?
儿玉次长 我们可以 自行指派任务吧？
Yes, please do that.
可以 拜托你们了
We at the Planning Division
我们经营企划部
will interview everyone who entered the sales floor.
会细查进入营业部楼层的人
PR is media.
公共关系部负责媒体
Administration, please have the data reissued.
行政部请重新核发资料
Why is Branch Inspection here?
稽核班为什么在会场？
I chose them to represent
我挑选他们
the Branch Managing Department.
代表分行管理部
They've resolved many issues within the bank.
他们解决过很多银行内部的问题
This is not a small issue within a branch.
这不是发生在分行内的小问题
This is a crisis that could rock the foundation of this bank's credibility.
这是可能撼动本银行信誉基础的危机
That's why Hanasaki's unique perspective
所以花琦独特的见解
will be of help.
会有帮助
Director Karashima.
辛岛部长
I spoke to the president the other day,
日前我和会长谈过
but during the next structural change, I plan to create a new department
下一次改变组织架构时 我打算在经营企划部内
within Corporate Planning, that will function as branch inspectors.
成立与分行稽核功能相同的新部门
What do you mean?
这是什么意思？
Then what will happen?
那么稽核班会怎么样呢？
Branch Inspection
稽核班
will be dissolved.
将会解散
Those two are always
那两个人
going beyond their role as branch inspectors.
总是逾越他们作为分行稽查员的分寸
-But… -Isn't it because of you?
-但是… -难道不是因为
Letting them do whatever they want?
你放任他们为所欲为吗？
BRANCH INSPECTION
（分行稽核班）
Wow.
真烦人
This many people came into this building on
6月20日那天有这么多人
June 20th?
进入这栋大楼？
It's more than I thought.
比我想的还多
We have to find someone suspicious out of all these people, right?
我们必须从这堆里面 找出可疑人士 对吧？
This is just a person making a delivery.
这只是一个送货的人
This won't give us any clues.
从这里得不到什么线索
VISITOR APPLICATION SLIP
（访客申请单）
Hey Hanasaki, let's say that what you said was true,
花琦 假设被你说对了
and someone did steal the data.
确实有人偷了资料
Do you have any idea who the culprit might be?
你有想到谁可能是犯人吗？
Not really…
没有
Just as I thought.
不出我所料
But it's someone who knows how the data is passed along, right?
不过那个人 清楚资料处理流程 对吧？
So it's someone within the bank.
所以是银行内部的人
Or so I think.
我认为是
And the motive?
动机呢？
The salary data has personal information on it such as
薪资资料里有个人信息
their full name and earnings.
例如全名和收入
-Yeah. -They might be selling that.
-对 -他们可能贩卖个人信息
But is that worth
但是牺牲掉
sacrificing your current job and future prospects for?
目前工作和未来前途值得吗？
You'd be dismissed if you were caught.
要是被抓会被开除的
That's true…
那倒是真的
Isn't it more realistic to think that
想成目的只是骚扰
it's just harassment?
会不会比较实际？
I see. Someone who has a grudge against our bank?
了解 某个对我们银行心怀怨恨的人
-Or against the Itami Group. -Yeah.
-或者对伊丹集团 -对
Or against Mr. Sakata.
或者对坂田先生
But Mr. Sakata isn't someone
可是坂田先生不是那种
who would incur someone's hatred.
会招致别人怨恨的人
He's really nice, diligent, and takes care of his subordinates.
他人好 勤奋 又照顾下属
It could be resentment.
可能是宿怨
I see.
这样啊
We don't have time for this.
我们没时间看这些
-What? -Mr. Soma, let's go to the Sales Division.
-什么？ -相马先生 我们去营业部
To do what?
去干嘛？
It's the scene of the crime.
那里是犯罪现场
We need to check the scene.
我们需要去现场查看
What are you, the police?
你是警察吗？
ITAMI HOLDINGS
（伊丹控股）
We're very sorry.
非常抱歉
You haven't found it yet?
你是什么意思？
What do you mean?
还没找到吗？
We set up an investigation committee so our employees can
我们成立了调查委员会
join forces together.
我们员工会齐心协力调查
Since this happened,
发生这种事
we will require a satisfactory explanation
对于发生的原因
of the cause of this incident.
我们需要一个满意的解释
Of course.
那是当然的
We will investigate the cause
我们会调查出原因
and report back.
向您报告
Mr. Shindo,
真藤先生
if by any chance the data is leaked,
万一资料外泄
I will no longer use your bank to finance
银座再开发计划
the Ginza Redevelopment Project.
将不再使用你们银行的贷款
And it seems like your bank's
而且前几天
Shinjuku Branch humiliated
你们的新宿分行
my son the other day.
似乎羞辱了我儿子
I'm very sorry.
我非常抱歉
But can you please give us time
但是在您做最后决定之前
before making your final decision?
可以给我们一点时间吗？
Chairman Itami, we will redeem ourselves
伊丹会长 我们会尽快解决这件事
by settling this issue as quickly as possible.
挽回我们的声誉
We're very sorry.
真的非常抱歉
-That's it, right? -Yeah.
-就是那个 对吧？ -对
Mr. Sakata.
坂田先生
Hey.
是你啊
Wow, Nanami.
是菜菜美
She's so big now.
她长好大了
She's in first grade now.
她上一年级了
Is that right? She probably doesn't remember me anymore.
是吗？她大概不记得我了
ITAMI HOLDINGS
（伊丹控股）
EISUKE SAKATA
（坂田荣介）
Mr. Sakata,
坂田先生
I'm sorry for being frank,
抱歉 我就直说了
but does someone have a grudge against you?
有人对你怀恨在心吗？
You're saying that the person who did this has a grudge against me?
你是说犯人对我怀恨在心吗？
That's a possibility.
有这个可能性
I can't think of anyone…
我想不出任何人
I see.
了解
I feel very bad
我对伊丹集团所有人
for everyone at the Itami Group.
感到非常抱歉
There are people
有的人
who need to pay for things on payday.
要在发薪日付款
I'm sorry.
抱歉
I have to go apologize to them again.
我必须再去向他们道歉一次
Excuse me.
我先走了
Should we ask the subordinates?
我们应该问他的下属吗？
Yes.
好
Did you see the magnetic tape with the Itami Group's salary data
你在上星期五有看到伊丹集团的
last Friday?
薪资资料磁带吗？
No, I did not.
我没看到
If I did, I would've delivered it.
我如果看到就会把它送过去
That was the routine, right?
那是例行程序 对吧？
Yes, Mr. Sakata came up with it.
是 是坂田先生提出的
I just did what Mr. Sakata told me to do.
我只是照坂田先生的话做
Do you suspect me
你们是怀疑我
of stealing it?
偷了它吗？
No, that's not it…
不是的
My job
我的工作
is to take the data from the locker to the Operation Center.
是将资料从置物柜拿去作业中心
And plus, the person in charge of transferring the salary
而且负责运送薪资资料的人
is Mr. Sakata.
是坂田先生
Everybody is so selfish.
每个人都好自私
What?
怎么说？
They're too busy trying to defend themselves.
他们都忙着捍卫自己
The only person thinking about the customers is Mr. Sakata.
唯一想着客户的人是坂田先生
You're right.
你说的没错
How disappointing.
真让人沮丧
-Ah. -Ouch!
好痛！
I'm sorry… oh.
对不起
Try to be more careful.
拜托小心一点
Do you know how much these cost?
你知道这鞋子花了多少钱吗？
I'm sorry.
对不起
Oh, Kameda.
龟田啊
-What? -Hello.
-怎么？ -你好
-You know each other? -He was my senior in university.
-你们认识啊？ -他是我大学学长
I'll be leaving now.
我要先走了
What are you doing with him?
你们找他干嘛？
Oh, let me guess.
我来猜猜
Because our company's data is lost?
因为我们公司的资料不见了？
Something like that.
差不多
That's a shame.
真丢脸
Is this bank all right?
这家银行还好吗？
Well, do your best.
你们好好努力
He's so annoying!
他真够烦人的
He was as arrogant as always.
他一如既往地傲慢
And he addressed the Itami Group as "our company."
而且他称伊丹集团为“我们公司”
Yes, he did.
没错
He's not aware that he's an employee at Tokyo Daiichi Bank.
他不认为自己是东京第一银行的员工
There's trouble.
出事了
Look how big it's being featured.
看看报纸怎么写的
What? Let me see it.
让我看一下
System trouble for Tokyo Daiichi Bank.
“东京第一银行系统故障”
10,000 people's salaries have been delayed.
“一万人薪资受拖延”
What's going on with the media?
媒体是怎么回事？
I'm very sorry.
我非常抱歉
What about the salary transfer for the Itami Group?
伊丹集团的薪资转账怎么样了？
We had the data reissued and processed right away,
我们立即重新核发和处理资料
but accounts with an outside bank will not get it today.
但是外面银行的账号今天收不到
What about everyone who entered the sales floor?
每个进入营业部楼层的人呢？
We talked with everyone
是 每一个识别卡号
whose ID card came up on the entry record, but we didn't find
出现在进出记录上的人我们都谈过
any lead.
未发现任何线索
We're also checking the security camera footage by the entrance,
我们也查看了入口监视器画面
but we haven't found anything
但是到目前
at the moment.
没有任何发现
That's not good enough!
这样不行！
-Branch Inspection? -Oh… um…
-稽核班呢？ -那个…
Nothing to note.
没有可报告的
Unbelievable…
怎么会？
What have you all been doing?
你们在搞什么？
Why did it disappear?
为什么会不见？
Where did the salary data go?
薪资资料去哪了？
Why doesn't anyone
为什么没有一个人
have any answers.
有答案？
Do whatever is necessary to give me
用尽一切必要方法
a satisfactory answer by tomorrow.
明天以前给我满意的答复
Yes, sir.
是
I guess even General Manager Shindo raises his voice like that, huh.
连真藤本部长都那样提高嗓门
It's a big problem that is putting his career at risk.
这么大的问题 会置他的职业生涯于风险中
I guess the life of a banker is pretty tough.
我猜银行从业者的生活很辛苦啊
Hey, Mai.
舞
You should give up on your dream of becoming a banker's wife.
你应该放弃成为银行业者妻子的梦想
It seems hard.
似乎不容易啊
How long are you planning to keep that up, Dad?
爸 你打算要提多久？
Don't get the wrong idea, Mr. Soma. Never even once
相马先生 你别误会
did I dream of becoming a banker's wife.
我一次也没有梦想过 要成为银行业者的妻子
Yes, you have.
你有
When? What year? What month? What day, and what time?
什么时候？ 哪年、哪月、哪天、几分、几秒？
I don't remember…
早忘了
Sakata?
是坂田啊
-From Sales Division Two? -His wife.
-营业二部那位？ -他太太
I'm friends with his wife too.
我和他太太也是朋友
Ms. Hanasaki, I heard that you met my husband today.
花琦小姐 我听说你今天遇到我先生
Please come visit us again.
请再来我们家玩
Nanami remembers you and wants to see you again.
菜菜美记得你 也很想再见到你
She's cute.
好可爱
It seems like
看来
Mr. Sakata didn't tell her about what happened at work.
坂田先生没有告诉他太太 工作上发生的事
-Mr. Soma. -Yeah?
-相马先生 -怎么？
Mr. Sakata won't be
坂田先生不会
dismissed because of this incident, will he?
因为这件事被解雇吧？
If the data was stolen, instead of being lost,
那个资料如果是被偷 而不是遗失
it will be the culprit's responsibility.
责任就在犯人
I don't know.
不知道呢
Mr. Sakata
坂田先生
is dedicated and is kind to his subordinates.
工作认真 对下属又好
He was always empathetic with the customer too.
他也总是用心对待客户
Those people should get promoted.
那样的人应该获得升迁
We have to find the culprit.
我们必须找到那个犯人
ITAMI HOLDINGS
（伊丹控股）
This is the data.
这就是那个资料
-What? -The Itami Group's salary data was found?
-什么？ -伊丹集团的薪资资料找到了？
Yes.
对
Where?
在哪里找到的？
The men's restroom on the seventh floor.
七楼男厕
What?
你说什么？
It was found within the bank,
在银行内找到了
but you don't know who did it?
但是不知道是谁做的？
We are investigating it right now.
我们正在调查
Were there traces of the file being opened by someone?
档案有被人打开过的痕迹吗？
No.
没有
Then the data won't be leaked?
那么资料没有外泄了？
It shouldn't be.
是 应该没有
That's a silver lining to all this.
真是不幸中的万幸
Finding the data
找到资料
hasn't resolved this case at all.
并没有解决这个案子
If it was found in the bathroom,
是在厕所发现的
it means that someone had taken it on purpose, right?
表示有人故意拿走它 对吧？
That's right.
没有错
So the culprit is within this bank.
所以犯人是银行内的人
That's highly possible.
那个可能性很高
-Let's find the culprit, Mr. Soma. -What?
-相马先生 我们去找出犯人 -什么？
The security camera.
去看监视器吧
The Planning Division combed through those vid--
我就说了 监视器画面 经营企划部早就看过了
They might have missed something.
他们可能漏看了什么
But still…
就算如此…
The culprit is definitely in the footage.
那个犯人肯定在监视器画面里
Someone in this bank caused everyone this trouble.
某个银行内的人给大家造成这个麻烦
It's unforgivable.
真是不可原谅
And if we find the culprit,
要是我们找到犯人
Mr. Sakata might not be punished.
坂田先生可能不会受到处罚
-But… -Okay, let's go Mr. Soma.
-可是… -我们走吧 相马先生
-What are you doing? -Let's hurry it up.
-你做什么？ -我们快点
-Ouch. -Hurry up.
-好痛！ -赶快
-This is the file for June 20th. -Thank you.
-这是6月20日的资料 -谢谢
Some people looked at this yesterday too.
昨天也有人看过
We apologize for bothering you again.
很抱歉又麻烦你们
There's so much traffic in this department.
这个部门进出的人好多
It's not just employees either.
而且也不是只有员工
But it only shows people going in and out.
不过它只显示人进人出
So it'll be difficult to find a clue here.
要从中找到线索很困难
Yes.
对
Oh, it's Mr. Sakata. He came back.
是坂田先生回来了
So the magnetic tape entered the building at this point.
所以磁带是在此时进入大楼
Yes.
对
This person…
这个人…
went in without using the ID card.
进去没有刷识别卡
It's the same person.
是同一个人
-It's the same person. -Did you find something?
-是同一个人 -你发现什么了吗？
This person went in without using his ID card,
这个人进去没有刷识别卡
and he's hiding behind someone when he comes out.
出来时又躲在某个人背后
How strange.
真奇怪
It's almost as if he doesn't want to leave a record of entering this floor.
好像他不想留下进入这层楼的记录
Right?
是吧？
Could this be the culprit?
他会不会就是犯人？
Who is this?
这个人是谁呢？
We can't tell because he's not showing his face.
他没有露脸 认不出来
What about characteristics? His suit, way of walking, or size?
特征呢？像是他的西装 走路方式或体型呢？
How can I find that…
那我要怎么找…
Mr. Soma…
相马先生
I think I found the culprit.
我想我找到犯人了
What?
嗯？
It was you?
是你啊
Why did you call me out here?
你把我叫来这里做什么？
I wanted to ask you something.
我有事情要问你
What? I don't care to talk with you.
什么？我懒得跟你说话
Mr. Itami.
伊丹先生
You're the one that stole the Itami Group's salary data.
伊丹集团的薪资资料是你偷走的
Am I right?
我说对了吗？
What?
什么？
What are you saying?
你在说什么啊？
We found evidence to prove that you're the culprit.
我们找到了证明你是犯人的证据
CORPORATE PLANNING DIVISION GENERAL MANAGER'S OFFICE
（经营企划部部长办公室）
What do you mean?
你是什么意思？
Our salary data
我们的薪资资料
was found in the bathroom
是在你们公司的厕所找到的
of your company but you still don't know who the culprit is?
可是你却还不知道犯人是谁？
I'm very sorry.
我非常抱歉
We are investigating it right now.
我们正在调查
Investigating it?
调查？
Don't tell me
别告诉我
that one of your employees did this.
是你们员工干的
If so,
如果是
this is a big problem.
这可是大问题
There's trouble! Mr. Seiichiro Itami…
出事了 伊丹清一郎先生…
What happened to him?
清一郎怎么了？
Ah…
那个…
Answer me!
回答我
This was captured from footage
这是截取的监视器画面
taken by the security camera of the sales floor last Friday.
是上星期五营业部那层楼的 监视器录下的
This person went in without using his ID card,
这个人进去没有刷识别卡
and a few minutes later
几分钟后
came out while hiding behind someone.
躲在别人后面出来
This is you, isn't it?
这个人是你 对吧？
On that day,
那天
you entered Sales Division Two without using your ID card
你没刷识别卡进入营业二部
and stole the Itami Group's salary data…
偷走伊丹集团的薪资资料
OUT TO OPERATION CENTER
（送往作业中心）
Then you left by hiding from the security camera.
离去时又跟在别人后面躲避监视器
If important data is lost, people will check
重要资料不见 大家会查看
everyone who entered the floor.
每一个进出该楼层人
That's why you didn't leave any record
所以你不留下刷卡记录
and hid from the camera.
还要躲着监视器
So that no one would ever suspect you.
这样就不会有人怀疑你
Stop this nonsense.
不要胡说八道了
How do you know that that person is me?
你怎么知道那个人是我？
What if you're wrong?
要是你错了呢？
-You still don't get it? -What?
-你还不懂吗？ -什么？
These are the expensive pair of shoes
这就是那双
that you're so proud of.
你非常引以为豪的鞋子
-Oh. -Ouch!
好痛！
Do you know how much these cost?
你知道这鞋子花了多少钱吗？
Why don't you confess?
你为什么不承认呢？
You can't make excuses anymore.
你无法再编借口了
We found out that you stole the data.
我们发现你偷了资料
But we couldn't figure out
但是我们不明白
how you knew the details
你是怎么知道
of the data processing.
资料处理过程的细节
Then we realized something.
然后我们注意到一点
You know someone in Sales Division Two.
营业二部有你认识的人
I told Mr. Itami about
我告诉伊丹先生
when the Itami Group's salary data will be sent in and how it's usually
伊丹集团的薪资资料何时送到
processed.
如何处理
And the password to the locker?
置物柜的密码呢？
I'm sorry.
对不起
Mr. Itami threatened me by saying,
伊丹先生威胁我 他说
"Do you know what will happen if you
“你知道如果不照我的话做
don't listen to me?"
你会怎么样吗？”
Mr. Kameda
龟田先生
told us everything.
把所有事情都告诉我们了
On June 20th,
6月20日那天
you stole the Itami Group's salary data,
你偷走伊丹集团的薪资资料
and then you placed it in the men's bathroom this morning.
今天早上又将它放在男厕内
ITAMI HOLDINGS
（伊丹控股）
Yeah, it was me.
对 是我
But so what?
可是那又怎样？
It's not a big deal.
没什么大不了的
I returned the data too.
我也归还了资料
Why did you do this?
你为什么要这样做？
It's revenge.
为了报复
For Tokyo Daiichi Bank.
东京第一银行
I thought I'd humiliate this bank.
我要羞辱这家银行
Humiliate?
羞辱？
I was treated badly at the Shinjuku Branch.
我在新宿分行受到恶劣对待
This bank is the worst.
这家银行最差劲了
But I'm forced to
我是被迫
do boring tasks here every day.
每天来这里做无聊的工作
I'm so sick and tired of it.
虽然厌烦 但又没办法走
I want to quit right away,
我想立刻辞职
but my dad tells me to stay here for two more years.
但是我爸要我在这里再待两年
You caused trouble
你给那么多人造成麻烦
for many people for of a reason like that?
只是为了那样的理由吗？
Stop exaggerating.
少大惊小怪了
All that happened was the salary was delayed.
也不过就是薪水延迟而已
Tokyo Daiichi Bank was humiliated a little bit,
东京第一银行受到一点点羞辱
but it didn't hurt anyone.
又没有伤害到任何人
You have worked at a bank
你已经在银行工作三年
for three years, and yet you don't know
却还不知道
how much trouble it causes people when their salary is delayed?
薪水延迟会对大家造成多少困扰？
I don't care.
我不在乎
Are you going to hit me?
你想揍我吗？
Do you know what will happen if you do that?
你知道你揍下去的话会怎样吗？
You'll get transferred for sure.
你肯定会被调职
Mr. Itami.
伊丹先生
You may not be able to stand
你可能无法忍受
working here at the bank.
在银行工作
But everyone who's working here is gritting their teeth
但是每个在这里工作的每个人
and doing their job
每一天都是咬紧牙关
every single day.
完成工作
Because that's what it means to work.
因为那就是工作
What you did
你所做的
is something despicable that insulted
是卑劣的行为 不仅侮辱了
not only everyone in this company
每个在这里工作的人
but every hard working employee
更侮辱世界上每一个
in this world.
努力工作的员工
You want to quit right away?
你想立刻辞职吗？
Give me a break.
别开玩笑了！
You are not qualified to work here in the first place.
你根本就不配在这里工作
Listen, Dad! These people are horrible!
爸 你听我说 这些人好可怕！
What have you done?
你做了什么好事？
Sorry for causing you trouble.
抱歉 给你们添麻烦了
I'm very sorry.
非常抱歉
Mr. Itami,
伊丹先生
please raise your head.
请抬起头来
I heard what you said.
我听到你们说的话
It seems like
看来我…
I didn't raise my son the right way.
没有把儿子教好
I have to teach him from the ground up.
我必须从头开始教他
Thank you for making me realize that.
谢谢你们让我意识到这一点
Seiichiro.
清一郎
Let's go.
我们走
You…
你啊
ran off on your own again.
又自作主张了
Good work, everyone.
大家辛苦了
Cheers!
干杯！
I was so surprised.
我太惊讶了
I didn't think Mr. Shindo and Chairman Itami would come.
没想到真藤本部长和伊丹会长会来
I really thought I was going to get punched.
我真的以为我要被揍了
You two are always making me worry.
你们两个总是让我担心
I've lost my appetite ever since Hanasaki came.
花琦来了之后 我胃口都没了
It's delicious.
好吃！
I'm happy to hear that, Mr. Shibasaki.
听芝崎先生这么说 我真高兴
I've heard about this place from Soma,
我听相马说过这里
but it's really delicious. Right, Mr. Karashima?
真的很好吃 辛岛部长？
Yes. I'll be coming by again.
是啊 我会再来光顾的
I don't want all of my bosses to come here.
我不想要我所有上司都来这里
Mr. Karashima, are you the one that recommended my daughter
辛岛部长 是你推荐我女儿
go to headquarters?
去总部的吗？
What are you asking?
爸 你怎么问这个？
Because there's no way you can go to
因为不靠有力人士推荐
headquarters without being recommended by someone with power.
你不可能去总部
It's not like you're especially talented or pretty
你又不是特别能干或漂亮
and you're strong-willed and scary.
而且你还意志坚强又可怕
Do you have to go that far?
你有必要扯这么远吗？
I chose Ms. Hanasaki.
是我选了花琦小姐
-What? -So it's true?
-什么？ -所以真的是你？
I heard about your work at the branch,
我听说了你在分行的表现
and I thought someone like you would be able to
我认为你这样的人
change the old-fashioned ways of the bank.
能改变银行守旧的作风
Thank you for thinking so highly
你那么看重我女儿
of my daughter.
非常感谢
Good for you, Hanasaki.
不简单呀 花琦！
That hurts.
好痛！真是的！
-This is on me! -Wow!
这个我请客
-Thank you. -It looks delicious.
-谢谢 -看起来好好吃
Wow. Thank you.
谢谢
Branch Inspection will be dissolved.
稽核班将会解散
-It's as good as always. -I'm glad.
-和以前一样好吃 -真高兴
-It's better than last year. -What?
-比去年的更好吃 -你说什么？
I thought we were done for,
我以为我们完了
but that seemed to be a blessing in disguise.
但却是因祸得福
Yes!
是
What should we do now?
我们应该怎么做呢？
Even the media found out about this scandal,
连媒体都发现这件丑闻了
so it will be trouble if they find out that it wasn't lost but that it was
要是他们知道资料不是遗失 而是遭员工偷窃
stolen by an employee.
麻烦就大了
What are you saying?
你在说什么？
What?
什么？
There was no theft by an employee.
没有员工偷窃这种事
The Itami Group's salary data
伊丹集团的薪资资料遗失
was lost because of mismanagement,
是因为管理问题
but it was safely found.
但是安全找到了
That's all that happened this time.
这次发生的事就是这样
This is an unexpected chance that you and the branch inspectors created.
这是你和那两个稽核员制造的 意想不到的机会
I will take full advantage of it.
我会充分利用的
EISUKE SAKATA ASSISTANT GM OF SALES DIVISION TWO
（营业二部次长 坂田荣介）
ISAO NAKAGAWA GM OF SALES DIVISION TWO
（营业二部部长 中河勋）
NEW POST HOKUETSU DAIICHI KOGYO NEW POST MORIMURAKAWA BRANCH
（新职务：北越第一工业 新职务：守村川分行）
Why?
怎么会？
Mr. Sakata is dispatched and Mr. Nakagawa is transferred.
坂田先生借调出去 中村部长调职
What does this mean?
这是什么意思？
They're forced to take responsibility for the incident with
他们被迫承担 这次伊丹集团薪资事件的
the Itami Group's salary data.
全部责任
But that was done by
可是那件事是
Seiichiro Itami and Kameda.
伊丹清一郎和龟田做的
They both admitted what they did and resigned.
他们都承认 也辞职了
It's General Manager Shindo.
是真藤本部长
What?
什么？
Our bank was chosen as the coordinating bank
我们银行获选为银座再开发计划的
for the Ginza Redevelopment Project.
主要银行
OUR BANK WAS CHOSEN…
（本银行获选为 银座再开发计划主要银行）
What does that have to do with this?
那个和这件事有什么关系？
General Manager Shindo used this incident
真藤本部长利用这个事件
as a negotiating tool.
作为谈判策略
To negotiate?
谈判策略？
On paper, both Itami junior and Kameda
白纸黑字上 伊丹公子和龟田
resigned voluntarily.
都是自愿离职
Therefore, the salary data was never stolen
那个薪资资料也没有
by an employee.
遭员工偷窃
No way!
怎么能这样？
By covering up the incident caused by Chairman Itami's son,
他靠掩盖伊丹会长儿子造成的事件
he got the position as coordinating bank for the hundred-billion-yen project.
获得千亿日元计划主要银行的位置
Mr. Sakata is going to be transferred because of that?
坂田先生因此要被借调出去？
It was only temporary, but the data did disappear.
这只是暂时的 不过资料确实不见了
The people in connection with it have to take the blame.
相关人员必须承担责任
It wouldn't set a good example if no one took the blame.
没有人承担责任 无法以儆效尤
BUS TERMINAL
（客运站）
I don't want to go!
我不想去
You can make new friends at your new school.
我们去新学校交新朋友
No, I want Mina.
不要 我要我的同学
I want Mina.
我要我的同学
Nanami.
菜菜美
I'll work hard at my new workplace too.
爸爸也会在新的地方努力工作
Let's work hard together, okay?
我们一起努力 好吗？
Ms. Hanasaki.
花琦小姐
Hanasaki.
花琦
-Thanks for coming. -No…
-谢谢你过来 -没什么
I'm not happy with this.
我不满意这个处置
Why do you have to be dispatched?
为什么你必须借调出去呢？
Someone always has to take responsibility.
总是有人要负起责任
That's how banks work.
这就是银行
-But what happened this time… -It's okay.
-可是这次的事… -没关系
I knew this would happen.
我知道会有这个结果
I'll be waiting.
我会等着
For you to come back.
等坂田先生回来
Hanasaki, a bank is…
花琦 银行的工作就是…
One X-mark and that's the end…
只要有一次失误 一切就结束了
right?
对吗？
But that's not right.
但那是不对的
What's wrong needs to be changed.
错误的事就应该改正
That's very you, Hanasaki.
不愧是花琦
Bye.
再见
Stay well.
保重
Thank you. Good luck, Mr. Sakata.
会的 坂田先生也保重
Yes.
是
How far did you go to see him off?
你是去多远送他？
Sorry.
抱歉
The meeting is going to start.
会议就要开始了
It's the last meeting with the investigation committee.
这是调查委员会最后一个会议
Didn't I tell you?
我没告诉你吗？
Hello?
喂？
Mr. Soma.
相马先生
What does it mean to work?
工作的意义是什么？
What now?
又怎么了？
Everything
每一件事
feels so meaningless.
感觉都毫无意义
What I thought was right
我认为是对的事
turned out to be wrong…
到头来却是错的
Is there a meaning to working hard
在一个似乎事事都错的地方
in a place where
努力工作
everything seems wrong?
有意义吗？
No matter what I do,
不论我做什么
or what I say,
说什么
I may not be able to change anything.
可能都无法改变任何事情
Hanasaki.
花琦
Yes.
是
I'm never going to repeat
我现在要说的话
what I'm about to say right now,
不会再说第二遍
so listen well.
所以你听好了
Okay.
是
Hanasaki.
花琦
You're not wrong.
你没有错
When something is wrong, you can say that it's wrong.
错误的事 你能直言它错了
That's a good thing.
那是优点
Having a subordinate who speaks out without
有一个不畏惧任何人
fearing anyone,
直言不讳的下属
is really tiring
对于一个上司来说
for a boss.
非常累人
But
但是
having one person like that…
有一个这样的人…
no, if we gradually get more and more people like that,
不 如果慢慢有越来越多这样的人
this bank that you're ready to give up on…
这个你准备要放弃的银行
may start to change.
可能会开始改变
Hurry up and come back.
赶快回来吧
Yes!
是！
Thanks to everyone's efforts,
感谢大家的努力
the incident with the Itami Group's lost salary data has been resolved,
伊丹集团薪资资料遗失事件已经解决
and we were able to get the position as the coordinating bank
我们也获得银座再开发计划
for the Ginza Redevelopment Project.
主要银行的位置
Soon, our bank will reign as the top bank
很快 本银行将成为全日本
in the nation.
最顶级的银行
All of you should carry a sense of pride
在座各位身为东京第一银行员工
as an employee of Tokyo Daiichi Bank.
应该感到自豪
There is something I'd like to ask General Manager Shindo.
真藤本部长 我有事情想请问你
Hey you. First, you're late, and you're being rude. Sit down.
你 首先你迟到了 而且你非常无礼 坐下
Why did Mr. Sakata and Mr. Nakagawa of Sales Division Two
为什么营业二部的 坂田先生和中河部长
get transferred?
遭到调职呢？
Hanasaki.
花琦
Is it because you used them as a negotiation tool for
是因为你利用这个作为
the Ginza Redevelopment Project?
银座再开发计划的谈判策略吗？
What are you saying? You're being very rude.
你在说什么？你太无礼了！
The data was never lost.
那个资料根本没有不见
Seiichiro Itami stole it because he resented this bank.
伊丹清一郎因为憎恨这个银行 而偷走它
In order to twist the truth and make it seem like the data was lost,
为了歪曲事实 让它看起来像不见了
you placed the blame on innocent people.
把责任推给无辜的人
That's wrong!
是不对的
I prioritized what was best for the bank.
我优先考虑怎么做对银行最有利
That's all.
如此而已
Then what's most important to you, is whatever
那么对真藤本部长最重要的事
benefits the bank?
就是只要对银行有利的事吗？
That's right.
没错
Let me ask you.
让我问你
What do you think is important?
你认为什么最重要呢？
The people.
人
I want the people at this bank to be the most important thing.
我希望在这间银行 工作的人是最重要的
With a naïve and idealistic theory like that,
以那么天真又理想化的理论
this bank will go down in three days.
这家银行三天就会堕落
Whatever benefits the bank will eventually
任何对银行有利的事
lead to the happiness of everyone working here.
终究会让这里所有员工幸福
With all due respect…
恕我直言
it's not everyone.
不是所有员工
There are people who suffer from injustice,
有人因为不公不义而受苦
and families who are affected by that.
还有因此受到影响的家人
It's wrong to pretend like
装作那些人不存在
those people do not exist.
是不对的
You've only been at this bank for five years
你只在银行待了五年
and have no knowledge of bank management.
而且对于银行管理一无所知
So what would you know?
你知道什么？
It's true that I don't know
没错 我是对银行管理
anything about bank management.
一无所知
Then shut up.
那就闭嘴！
No, I will not!
我不要！
I don't know about management,
我不懂管理
but I know that it's wrong for hardworking people
但是我知道让在银行里努力工作的人
at this bank to be
像颗棋子那样被移来移去
moved around like chess pieces!
是不对的
Ever since I started working at Branch Inspection,
自从我在稽核班工作以来
I've come across many people.
遇到了很多人
This bank
这间银行
has many people who are working diligently for themselves,
有许多为了自己、家人和朋友
their family, and their friends.
兢兢业业工作的人
Those people are
这些人
harassed by their bosses,
受到上司骚扰
blamed for their boss's mistakes,
替上司承担过错
and called incompetent…
还有人被说成无能的人
It's wrong for people's lives to be affected by words like
人们的生活受到 “以儆效尤”或者“按照惯例”
"setting an example" or "formality."
这些词的影响是不对的
It's wrong that hardworking people
认真工作的人无法幸福
can't be happy.
是不对的
This bank
这间银行
is full of wrong things.
充满了不对的事情
It's wrong?
不对吗？
Then what should we do?
那么应该怎么做呢？
I think it needs to be changed.
我认为需要改变
Do you think you can change it?
你认为你有能力改变吗？
Yes, I do.
是
Then try it.
那么就试试看吧
I'm sorry for Hanasaki's rude behavior.
对于花琦无礼的行为 我感到很抱歉
Director Karashima.
辛岛部长
About the dissolvement of the Branch Inspection…
关于解散稽核班的事
Yes.
是
I've decided to put that off for now.
我决定暂缓
Really?
真的吗？
Yes.
是
I decided on that just now.
我决定暂时保留
Thank you.
谢谢
But why?
但是为什么呢？
-Is it good? -Yes.
-好吃吗？ -好吃
I'm so happy.
好幸福啊
Mai, didn't you get your bonus?
舞 你没拿到奖金吗？
pay your tab with your bonus?
你要用奖金来付账单吗？
Oh no! I bought clothes already.
糟糕 我拿去买衣服了
Did you say something?
你说什么？
Nothing. I'll pack the rest for lunch.
没什么 剩下的我要带便当
Mai. Hold on. Wait.
舞 等一下
-Thank you. -What?
-感谢招待 -怎么回事？
She's hopeless.
真拿她没办法
It's delicious!
真好吃
I'm surprised. I never thought you would ever
我非常诧异 没想到真藤本部长
approve of those two from Branch Inspection.
会认可那两个稽核班的
When did I say that?
我何时说过那种话？
Oh, but…
可是
you're going to keep Branch Inspection, right?
您要留下稽核班 不是吗？
I said, "for now."
我说“暂时”
I'll take my time to observe.
我会慢慢观察
Yes, sir.
是
Hanasaki Mai…
花琦舞
Why are you so stubborn?
你为什么这么顽固？
With all due respect…
恕我直言
this isn't about stubbornness. It's preference.
这与顽固无关 这是偏好
-Deep-fried mackerel is best with a sauce. -No, soy sauce!
-炸鲭鱼最适合配酱汁！ -配酱油！
It's delicious when the thick sauce
浓稠的酱汁
seeps into the crispy fried mackerel.
渗入酥炸的鲭鱼超美味
The sauce is too heavy.
那个酱汁太重了
The soy sauce is nice and simple.
酱油爽口又简单
We'll never see eye to eye.
我们永远无法有共识
I guess so.
我想也是
I'm waiting for an inspection at Nippori Branch
我等着去日暮里分行稽核
because there's a really good restaurant near there.
那附近有一间很棒的餐厅
The Niigata special called Italian sounds nice too.
新泻的意大利面看起来也不错
What is that?
那是什么？
There's tomato sauce on top of the yakisoba.
炒面上面加番茄酱
I've never heard of that. That looks really good.
我从来没听过 看起来很不错
It's so hot today!
今天好热
-It's an inspection. -Where?
-有分行要稽核 -在哪里？
-Which branch? -It's Ni…
-哪家分行？ -是…
-Niigata? -Nippori, right?
-新泻？ -日暮里吧？